wbponline.com 2011-06-05

# World Business Press online

## Scope

This Privacy Policy covers WBP's online treatment of personally identifiable information that we collect when you are on a WBP online Web site and when you use our services. This policy also covers our treatment of any personally identifiable information that our business partners share with us.

This policy does not apply to the practices of companies that WBP online does not own or control, or to individuals that WBP online does not employ or manage, including operators of sites to which you may link from the WBP online Web sites. This policy also does not apply to any offline collection of personally identifiable information or the treatment of the same when such information is collected outside of the WBP online Web site.

## What information do we gather?

The only individually identifiable information that we collect about you is that which you choose to share with us in registration, when using our products and services, or when responding to offers from WBP online or from our business partners.

We also collect information about aggregate site usage. Statistics that we gather about unique visits, referring URLs, repeat visits and page views are all based on IP address, and are not associated with your personal information.

## Why do we ask for personal information about you?

Our ultimate goal at WBP online is to provide you with a comprehensive set of actionable financial news, data and tools to assist you in making decisions about your investments. Many of the features on our Web site will be more beneficial to you if you customize the way they work and what they contain, and then can return to your personalized version each time you come back to the Web site. Personal Portfolios are the most obvious example of this type of feature. To support this personalization we need to be able to identify your account from session to session. This requires that you provide us with some individually identifiable information about yourself. Your user name, password and email address allow us to differentiate you from other users and maintain your personalized version of the Web site. They also allow us to contact you about developments and new products on the Web site.

Other information that we ask you to share with us allows us to improve the Web site. Aggregate demographic information about our users is valuable to our advertisers as it provides them with more effective channels for reaching potential customers.

We share aggregate information with our partners and advertisers. We will not share your personally identifiable information with any third party, unless we tell you otherwise when we collect the information, you have consented by "opting in" to being contacted by WBP online, its third party partners or advertisers, or we have informed you of a change to our privacy policy so that you can then choose to opt out. We will give you a way to "opt out" of being contacted by WBP online.

In short, the information you provide us can help us to understand how to make our Web site more convenient and useful to our audience.

## Opting-Out. Here is how it works at WBP online: 

We do not share personally identifiable information with anyone, unless we tell you otherwise when we collect the information, you "opt in" to having your information shared with third parties, or we have informed you of a change to our privacy policy so that you can then choose to opt out. It's that simple.

When we ask you for personally identifiable information, we will tell you if we intend to share it with others. We will provide you with a way to tell us that you don't want us to share the information or if you don't want to receive promotional and/or marketing information about products, services, and offerings from WBP online and/or any third parties. We will also provide you with a way to update your personally identifiable information that you share with us during registration. Once you have "opted in" and agreed that your information may be shared with third parties or you have responded to an offer by any third party on the WBP online Web sites, WBP online can no longer update any of your personally identifiable information that has been transferred to such third parties or opt you out of such third parties so that you no longer receive their promotional and/or marketing information. Instead, you must either contact that third party or refer to their privacy policy to update your personally identifiable information or to let them know that you no longer want to receive promotional and/or marketing information about their products, services, or offerings.

## How does WBP online use cookies?

WBP online uses cookies to facilitate the login process for you across multiple applications on our Web sites. Everything we learn from your activity will be used to enrich your experience on our Web sites. It will help us understand what you like and don't like, so we can focus our energies more effectively and provide you with better financial news and data. There are 2 types of cookies that we use.

The first type of cookie has no personal information attached to it and is used to count unique users. That cookie can also be used for advertising purposes by WBP online, its business partners and advertisers, for serving and delivering advertising campaigns to control frequency of exposure, or to target by domain name, time zone or geographic location.

For any user who subsequently registers with our site, we replace the first type of cookie with a user identifiable cookie, which we continue to use for unique user counting as well as advertising targeting, but that cookie may now also include personally identifiable information. This cookie allows you to access all of your personalized areas of the Web site without having to log on multiple times.

Lastly, there may be a third party cookie in WBP online emails that is generated by our business partners or advertisers when they sponsor emails to promote their products and services.

## What information do we gather?

The only individually identifiable information that we collect about you is that which you choose to share with us in registration, when you use our products and services that require you to provide personal information about yourself, when responding to offers from WBP online or from our business partners or advertisers, or when responding to surveys from us or our third party business partners (including without limitation surveys for online advertising brand effectiveness). As stated earlier, this information will be closely protected and used for internal purposes only, unless we tell you otherwise when we collect the information, you have consented by "opting in" to being contacted by WBP online, its partners and advertisers, and other third parties, or we have informed you of a change to our privacy policy so that you can then choose to opt out. We will never willfully release your personal information to any third party without providing you notice unless: you direct us to enter you in a contest; sign you up for a service which is sponsored by one of our partners; you otherwise "opt in" to have your information shared with third parties; we respond to subpoenas, court orders or legal process; we find your actions on our Web site violate our Terms of Use or any of our usage guidelines for specific products or services (and then only to pursue appropriate action); or we transfer your information in connection with a sale, merger, transfer, exchange, or other disposition (whether assets, stock, or otherwise), of all or a portion of a business of WBP online. If, however, as a result of the business transfer your personal information will be used in a new and different manner, then you will have a choice as to whether to allow this new use.

We also collect information about aggregate Web site usage. Statistics that we gather about unique visits, repeat visits and page views are all based on IP address, not on your individual activities.

The information we gather is supplemented with information provided by third party sources and may be used to derive additional data to enhance our databases. For example, zip code information you provide may be used to derive city and state information or may be used to add demographics data.

## Changes to the WBP online Privacy Policy 

WBP online may amend this policy from time to time. If we make any substantial changes in the way we use your personal information we will notify you by posting a prominent notice in our privacy policy or in other locations on our Web site or by sending you an email to inform you of our updated privacy policy. Users will have a choice as to whether or not we use their information in this different manner. However, if users have opted out of all communication with the Web site, or deleted/deactivated their account, then they will not be contacted, nor will their personal information be used in this new manner.

## The Bottom Line 

Sometimes we want personal information from you so that we, our partners and our advertisers, can send you some material we think might be of interest to you if you have so opted.

We promise never to be sneaky about getting this information from you. We always tell you up front what we're going to do with the personal information you have provided, and we always give you a chance to say "no thanks."
